[Music]
mcdonald's are releasing the
shamrock milkshake again and if you
don't know what that is
that is a very special kind of milkshake
that they released i think
back in the 60s originally or 69
something like that
it's a vanilla ice cream with a touch of
mint flavoring
and made green most people go wrong
making this with
actual mint ice cream and that's that's
where the problem is it's not it's
vanilla ice cream
but just with a little bit of mint on
top so we're actually going to create
the milkshake and the other one that
they're releasing which is
the shamrock oreo mcflurry
i mean that's pretty self-explanatory
but you'll be able to make
the milkshake even if you don't have an
ice cream maker
the actual mcflurry might be a bit
harder because it's a soft serve so
you're not going to
really be able to create that as using a
non-churn ice
cream i mean you could try it would
probably taste okay but
you know if you've got an ice cream
machine it would just make life much
easier
so we're going to jump right in and make
the milkshake
ice cream first then when that's done
we're going to stick it in the freezer
and go on to the next one so stick
around
and as i said most people go wrong when
trying to recreate this they
use a mint ice cream and it really does
give you a totally different flavor
mcdonald's it's a vanilla ice cream with
a little bit of mint and then the green
coloring
so to make this combine your milk and
your sugar into a bowl and give it a
really good whisk
you want that sugar to dissolve and then
at that point add your skim milk powder
and put it in the fridge
if you've seen some of my videos before
you know i love skim milk powder so it's
the same kind of process
leave it in there for 20 minutes take it
out and give it another good stir
at that point add your cream and your
vanilla so in this case it's two
teaspoons of vanilla
give it a quick taste test and then add
a touch of mint and i mean
it's a touch it's a sixteenth of a
teaspoon something like that
once you've put that in finally add the
green coloring again you can make it as
bright or as dull green as you like it's
completely up to you
give it one final stir and then pour it
into your ice cream machine
this will take somewhere 20-25 minutes
you know on the bigger machines 15
minutes
once it's ready get it batched into your
container
and put it in your freezer
[Music]
so now we're making the mcflurry ice
cream as i said this is exactly the same
as the milkshake ice cream so
i won't go through it all again sit back
and enjoy a few seconds of music
[Music]
[Applause]
right so now it's five minutes ish
before the churning's done
we're going to add in our crushed oreos
we're only going to put in about 75
of them we want to leave some to the end
to decorate
once the churning is done we're going to
take the ice screen maker off the table
and bring everything back and start
loading it into the glass
right so before we get the milkshake ice
cream out the freezer
we're going to load up the cream whipper
because we're going to need to use that
after
so we'll just do that now and then we'll
probably put it back in the fridge just
for five minutes while we get everything
else ready
[Music]
so this is the ice cream that we made
earlier
been in the freezer for a good few hours
we're gonna
get this into the blender and make
milkshake
okay now this is ready to
go into our glass let me try and remove
this first
[Music]
all right so that's the milkshake almost
done we need to do the cream we're going
to get the ice cream straight out of the
freezer now it's been in there for
about three minutes once we do this and
get the mcflurry into the glass
okay we've got everything here i think
to do this obviously that's our
milkshake waiting for the cream
we've got our mcflurry if you will it's
sat in here let's load this
into the glass i mean it instantly looks
much better than
the mcdonald's mcflurries they're
horrendous i i don't even know if you
can really call that ice cream it's just
i don't know semi-frozen cream
it's not particularly pleasant there's
no flavor you know how that works
but um obviously this shamrock version
has a slightly stronger vanilla flavor
and that mint there as well
so there we go put that out the way give
that to my wife there you go
and just top this one off and sprinkle
on
some of the last little bits of oreo
right let's just top this up with cream
like that and there we go
the shamrock milkshake and shamrock
oreo mcflurry from mcdonald's quite
stressful to get all these done and all
sat here looking like this at the same
time gotta admit
hence why we're in the kitchen doing
this rather than in our normal place
but there you go a soft serve
mcflurry with oreo bits mainly vanilla
flavor with a little bit of
mint in there what does it taste like
tastes identical to mcflurry but
much better quality much creamier so you
actually get flavour come through there
you get that vanilla come through
but you don't get the overpowering taste
of mint just get a little bit just
enough
to make it taste a little like mint and
i think that's the difference
if you were to make this with mint ice
cream that's all you get you don't get
any
vanilla but the shamrock is a vanilla
ice cream
so it's a big difference there so that's
really nice actually
it's been a while since i had one of
these it's been a while since anyone's
been able to leave their home
so you know why is that a shock
the shamrock milkshake like i said it's
the same it's the same ice cream
essentially just without the oreos
what does this taste like
that's also really good and you actually
lose a little bit
obviously when you blend this up with
milk you lose a little bit of that
flavor so if i were to make this again
i'd probably put a little bit more of
everything in so harder on a vanilla a
little bit harder on the mint
but ultimately not too bad so
hopefully you can try these at home you
can get that shamrock flavor that
everyone seems to love
let me know how it goes if you do make
these thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like and subscribe the
next video
is gonna be a vegan one so we're gonna
try and recreate
jude's vegan chocolate brownie ice cream
so hopefully you'll join us for that one
thanks very much
see you next time